Guide to the Ralph W. Tyler Papers 1932-1988
University of Chicago Library
- Series V: Writings by Others
  - Subseries 1: Reports
    - Report of the University of Massachusetts School of Education Advisory Committee. April 30, 1982 (Box 80, Folder 15)
    - Report of the Third Annual Conference of the Eight Year Study (1935) (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Report of the President's Task Force on Education (1964) (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - Report of the President's Task Force on Older Americans, pgs. 1-23 (1968) (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - Report of the President's Task Force on Older Americans, pgs. 24-263, Appendices A-F (1968) (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - Report of the Reviewers of the Graduate Department of Education Foundations Division (Box 81, Folder 5)
  - Subseries 2: Articles and Manuscripts
    - American Psychological Association (APA), "Guidelines for Nonsexist Language in APA Journals," June 1977 (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - Blake, Judith, various (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - Jochums, Brenda L. and M. Virginia Biggy, "Computers and Related Technological Devices in Education, "(3 copies and notes) (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - K, authors, Keegan, Frank L., various Kizer, George, "The Problems of Biography: The Living Legend," 1983. Koech, Michael (Box 81, Folder 9)
    - M-T, authors, Miller, James Grier Moore, Diana and Elizabeth Sturtz Schiller, Diana Tyler, E. Carolyn (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - U-W, authors, Unknown Weedon, Vivian Wolf, W.C. (Box 82, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 3: Dissertations
    - Ismail, Ahmed Mohamed El-saman, "Ralph Tyler and Curriculum Evaluation with Reference to Egyptian Education," University of Connecticut, 1984. (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - Muhamad, Mazanah, "Ralph W. Tyler’s Perspectives on Designing and Facilitating Adult Learning," North Carolina State University, 1987. (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - Stone, Maria Kirchner, "Ralph W. Tyler’s Principles of Curriculum, Instruction and Evaluation: Past Influences and Present Effects," Loyola University of Chicago, 1985. (Box 82, Folder 5)
- Series VI: Audio-Visual
  - Subseries 1: Reel to Reel Audio Tape
    - Highlights of the 1965 White House Conference on Education. (Box 83)
    - Interview, Ralph W. Tyler and Ervin Lewis, CBS Radio, 1965. (Box 83)
    - Speech, Ralph W. Tyler, Newcomb Hall, South Meeting Hall, undated. (Box 83)
    - Speech, Ralph W. Tyler, "A Curriculum Rationale," undated. (Box 83)
    - Lecture, Ralph W. Tyler, "Community and School Curriculum," Spring Conference, Vancouver, Canada, 1967. (Box 83)
    - Interview, Ralph W. Tyler, "Education of Children in Other Countries," Longhorn Radio Network, Austin, TX, 1972. (Box 83)
  - Subseries 2: Audio tapes
    - W. Clement Stone Press Conference, Conservative Vice Lords, September 10, 1970. (Box 84)
    - 2 interviews: Pressy with Tyler, December 11, 1970; Stoddard with Tyler, February 18, 1972. (Box 84)
    - Ralph W. Tyler, "The Schools of the Future: Needed Research and Development," Alternative Futures for Education and Learning, Symposium 1973. (Box 84)
    - "Conversations from Wingspread," Action Learning - Opportunities for Youth, The Johnson Foundation, 1974. (There is an accompanying form to go along with the tape, which can be found in Series VII, Oversize Box, Folder 18). (Box 84)
    - Ralph Tyler, Richard Jaeger, Alexander Law, W. James Popham, and Daniel Stufflebeam, "Expanding Technology of Educational Evaluation," 1974. (Box 84)
    - "What Can We Expect from Tests?" Michigan School Testing Conference, March 13, 1974. (Box 84)
    - R. W. Tyler and J. I. Goodlad, "Curriculum Development and the Tyler Rationale, " Dialogue on American Education, 1974. (For this collection of tapes for the Dialogue on American Education there is a supplemental study guide that can be found in Series VII, Oversize Box, Folder 20). (Box 84)
    - R. W. Tyler and J. I. Goodlad, "Condition on Schooling Today," Dialogue on American Education, 1974. (Box 84)
    - R. W. Tyler and J. I. Goodlad, "School Organization and Reform," Dialogue on American Education, 1974. (Box 84)
    - R. W. Tyler and J. I. Goodlad, "Future Directions in Education," Dialogue on American Education, 1974. (Box 84)
    - R. W. Tyler and J. I. Goodlad, "Curriculum Development and the Tyler Rationale, " Dialogue on American Education, 1974. (copy 2) (Box 84)
    - R. W. Tyler and J. I. Goodlad, "Condition on Schooling Today," Dialogue on American Education, 1974. (copy 2) (Box 84)
    - R. W. Tyler and J. I. Goodlad, "School Organization and Reform," Dialogue on American Education, 1974. (copy 2) (Box 84)
    - R. W. Tyler and J. I. Goodlad, "Future Directions in Education," Dialogue on American Education, 1974. (copy 2) (Box 84)
    - R. W. Tyler, "A Perspective on Declining Test Scores," 1977. (Box 84)
    - Ralph W. Tyler, "Curriculum Development," Conversations from Wingspread, 1978. (Box 84)
    - Ralph W. Tyler, "Education in the People's Republic of China," Conversations from Wingspread, 1978. (Box 84)
    - Ralph W. Tyler, "Minimum Competency Testing," Conversations from Wingspread, 1978. (Box 84)
    - Unidentified recording (Box 84)
    - Tyler Meeting 1 (Box 84)
    - Tyler Meeting 2 (Box 84)
    - Ralph Tyler, I.D.E.A. - Research & Development Division, Westwood Center, Suite 950, 1100 Glendon Ave., Los Angeles, CA 90024. (Box 85)
    - Ralph Tyler (?), "Insight/Education - How Good Are Our Schools?" (Box 85)
    - Miami Panel, Sides 1 & 2, April 14, 1978. (Box 85)
    - Miami Panel, Sides 1 & 2, April 15, 1978. (Box 85)
    - Miami Panel, Sides 3 & 4, April 15, 1978. (Box 85)
    - Miami Panel, Sides 5 & 6, April 15, 1978. (Box 85)
    - Orlando Panel, Sides 1 & 2, April 13, 1978. (Box 85)
    - Orlando Panel, Sides 1 & 2, April 14, 1978. (Box 85)
    - Tallahassee Panel, Sides 1 & 2, April 16, 1978. (Box 85)
    - Tallahassee Panel, Sides 3 & 4, April 16-17, 1978. (Box 85)
    - Tallahassee Panel, Sides 5 & 6, April 17, 1978. (Box 85)
    - Tallahassee Panel, Sides 7 & 8, April 17, 1978. (Box 85)
    - Tallahassee Panel, Rev. R. N. Gooden, 7:30 p.m. (Box 85)
    - "A Century of Testing in American Education," Michigan School Testing Conference, March 6, 1979. (Box 85)
    - "Politics of Educational Decline," Sides 1 & 2, Teach'em, 1979. (Box 85)
    - "Politics of Educational Decline," Sides 3 & 4, Teach'em, 1979. (Box 85)
    - "School Reform," Sides 1 & 2, Teach'em, 1979. (Box 85)
    - "Education and Human Potential," AASA Distinguished Lecture, February 16, 1981. (Box 85)
    - Ralph Tyler, "38th Biennial Council Speech," Chicago, 1981. (Box 85)
    - Ralph Tyler, "38th Biennial Council Speech," Chicago, 1981. (copy 2) (Box 85)
    - Ralph Tyler, "Teacher Burnout: Disease and Cure," (American Educational Research Association) AERA Annual Meeting, Los Angeles April 13-17, April 16, 1981. (Box 85)
    - Ralph Tyler, "Neglected But Necessary Sources of Curriculum Knowledge," (American Educational Research Association) AERA Annual Meeting, Los Angeles April 13-17, April 15, 1981, Part I. (Box 86)
    - Ralph Tyler, "Neglected But necessary Sources of Curriculum Knowledge," (American Educational Research Association) AERA Annual Meeting, Los Angeles April 13-17, April 15, 1981, Part II. (Box 86)
    - "Education in Transition," Keynote Address, National Association of State Boards of Education, Annual Meeting, New Orleans, October 13, 1983. (Box 86)
    - "Educational Research: Uses, Abuses, and Non-Uses," American Educational Research Association Conference, 1984., This item has been reformatted for access. (Box 86)
    - Ralph Tyler, "Curriculum Balance," Sides 1 & 2, March 23, 1985., This item has been reformatted for access. (Box 86)
    - Ralph Tyler, "Curriculum Balance," Sides 3 & 4, March 23, 1985., This item has been reformatted for access. (Box 86)
    - "Policy Research Voids in School Supervision," American Educational Research Association Conference, 1986., This item has been reformatted for access. (Box 86)
    - "Trump Memorial Lecture," NASSP, 1987. (Box 86)
    - "The 28th Charles W. Hunt Lecture: Education in the Year 2000," 2nd General Session, American Association of Colleges for Teacher Education, 1987. (Box 86)
    - Rethinking the Curriculum for the Next Decade, Association for Supervision and Curriculum Development (ASCD), Audio Cassette Series, 6 Tape Set, 1990. (Box 86)
  - Subseries 3: Videotapes
    - "Conversation with...Dr. Tyler," Interviewed by Dr. J. G. Miller, University of Louisville, I. C. C., May 1, 1979. (Box 87)
    - "Restoring Confidence in Our Schools," ASCD, 1980. (Box 87)
    - "Curriculum Rationale," loose film role. (Box 87)
    - Southern Poverty Law Center, undated. (Box 88)
    - Ralph Tyler Lecture Series, "Learning - For Living and For Work," Episodes 1 & 2, March 31, 1983. (Box 88)
    - Ralph Tyler Lecture Series, "Learning - For Living and For Work," Episodes 3 & 4, April 1, 1983. (Accompanying pamphlet in Series VII, Oversize Box 90, Folder 19). (Box 88)
    - Historical Perspectives on American Education, "Relating Theory and Practice in the Education of Teachers," Program 1, 1985. (There was an accompanying order form, which can be found in Series VII, Oversize Box, Folder 18). (Box 88)
    - Historical Perspectives on American Education, "The Contributions of School in Developing a Literate Citizenship," Program 2, 1985. (Box 88)
    - Historical Perspectives on American Education, "The Changing Roles of Testing and Evaluation," Program 3, 1985. (Box 88)
    - Historical Perspectives on American Education, "Helping in the Transition from Youth to Adulthood," Program 4, 1985. (Box 88)
    - Historical Perspectives on American Education, "Development and Use of Technology in Education," Program 5, 1985. (Box 88)
    - Historical Perspectives on American Education, "The Struggle for Equality of Access to Quality Education," Program 6, 1985. (Box 88)
- Series VII: Restricted
  - General Correspondence, A (Box 89, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence, B (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence, C (Box 89, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, D (Box 89, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence, E (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Fellowships and Scholarships (Box 89, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence, F-H (Box 89, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence, M-O (Box 89, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence, P (Box 89, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence, S (Box 89, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence, W (Box 89, Folder 11)
- Series VIII: Oversize
  - American Council on Education; Cooperative Study in General Education. Galley proofs for "General Education in the Social Studies", by Albert William Levi, 1948 (Box 90, Folder 1)
  - Institutional Pattern Map (1947?) (Box 90, Folder 2)
  - Proposed Budget for the Study of Educational Progress, 1947-8 (Box 90, Folder 3)
  - "Articles of Incorporation, As Amended and Adopted June 10, 1946." (Box 90, Folder 4)
  - National Society for the Study of Education, Forty- Fourth Yearbook, Practice in Curriculum Development, Chapter XIII (galley proof) by Prudence Cutright. (Box 90, Folder 5)
  - Hull House Assistantship, Expenditures, 1940 (Box 90, Folder 6)
  - Hull House Assistantship, Expenditures, 1941 (Box 90, Folder 7)
  - Hull House Assistantship, Expenditures, 1942 (Box 90, Folder 8)
  - Hull House Assistantship, Expenditures, 1943 (Box 90, Folder 9)
  - Class materials for curriculum seminar at Hebrew University in Jerusalem, 1974. (Box 90, Folder 10)
  - Class materials for curriculum seminar at Hebrew University in Jerusalem, 1975 (Box 90, Folder 11)
  - "Some Items of Progress in the Schools if District 99, Cicero, IL," February 6, 1947. (Box 90, Folder 12)
  - Address by the Honorable William Benton, Assistant Secretary of State, March 3, 1947 (Box 90, Folder 13)
  - "Characteristics of Traditional Schools," excerpts from the Philadelphia Public School Survey, 1937. (Box 90, Folder 14)
  - Surveys of Schools, Dalton School Survey, 1940 (Box 90, Folder 15)
  - Surveys of Schools, Dalton School Survey, Exhibits A-I (Box 90, Folder 16)
  - Surveys of Schools, Dalton School Survey, Exhibits J-Z (Box 90, Folder 17)
  - Historical Perspectives on Education, order form, (came with set of lecture tapes found in Box 88). (Box 90, Folder 18)
  - Ralph Tyler Lecture Series, pamphlet for videotapes found in Box 88. (Box 90, Folder 19)
  - John I. Goodlad and Ralph W. Tyler, Dialogue on American Education, (Glendale, CA: Educational Resource Associates), 1974. Accompanied a set of tapes found in Box 84. (Box 90, Folder 20)
  - Conversations from Windspread, July 17, 1978. (Box 90, Folder 21)